数千年来
For many millennia,
权威者统治着天堂王国
the Authority has ruled in the Kingdom of Heaven
控制着一切
with absolute control.
他自诩为创世主  天父  全能的神
He named himself the Creator, the Father, the Almighty.
但那是一派胡言
He is none of those
他与我们一样  只是天使
but just an angel like ourselves.
一个黑暗天使在旁辅佐他的统治
And he rules with a dark angel by his side.
我们为真相而战  却被从天堂驱逐
We, who fought for truth, were cast out of the Kingdom.
此后  我们在世界之间穿梭
Since then, we have lived between the worlds,
观察  伺机复仇
watching and waiting for vengeance.
人类中间迸发出了希望的火苗
A spark of hope is alive among humankind.
一位大胆的领袖在召集勇士
A bold leader is rallying warriors.
他虽是凡人
He may be mortal...
但他的野心超越了同类
but his ambitions transcend his kind.
一条毒蛇受到了召唤
A serpent has been summoned.
一个新夏娃出现了
A new Eve emerges.
新的反叛时刻
The time for a new rebellion
即将来临
is coming.
莱拉
Lyra!
我在找一个女孩
I'm looking for a girl.
中等身高  黑发  棕色的眼睛
Medium height, dark hair, brown eyes.
她叫莱拉  她的精灵叫潘
Her name's Lyra. She has a daemon called Pan.
她不见了
She's missing.
帮帮我
Help me.
告诉我她在哪
Tell me where she is.
潘
Pan?
莱拉
Lyra!
罗杰  是你吗
Roger! Is that you?
我需要你  帮帮我
I need you! Help me!
你在哪
Where are you?
罗杰
Roger!
莱拉
Lyra.
翻译
黑暗草
时间轴
念念
后期  吉吉
校对|总监  草草
改编自菲利普·普尔曼原著
黑暗物质
第三季 第一集
拜托  加把劲
Come on. Come on.
天啊
For goodness' sake.
飞行器可能还没准备好
The craft may not be ready for this.
那就得怪我们俩了  是吧
Then that is on the pair of us, is it not?
清空思绪
Clear your mind.
后振荡器坏了
We've lost the rear oscillator.
做好准备
Brace!
你从小径上过来时我就闻到了花香
I could smell the flowers when you came down the path.
你好吗
How are you?
怎么了
What's wrong?
出什么事了吗
Is there a problem?
礼拜堂已经空置多年了
This chapel has stood empty for years.
有传言说有人躲在里面
There are rumours that someone is hiding there.
我不是在躲
I'm not hiding.
你为什么在这里
Why are you here?
你相信魔法吗
Do you believe in magic?
有时信
Sometimes.
跟我来
Follow me.
别害怕
Don't be scared.
她是我女儿
She is my daughter.
有个巫师对她施了咒语
An enchanter has cast a spell on her...
所以她在睡觉
...that's why she's asleep.
你不能叫醒她吗
Can't you wake her?
我需要时间帮她醒过来
I need time to help wake her up.
我需要你帮我拦住外人
I need you to help me keep the people away.
我帮你
I will help.
谢谢  太感谢了
Thank you, I appreciate it.
请保护好她
Keep her safe, please.
一定
I will.
这是我们的秘密
This is our secret.
求你
Please...
放我们走
...let us go.
来
Here.
喝下去
Drink this.
如果你不喝药
If you don't drink your medicine,
又怎么能好起来呢  亲爱的
how will you get better, darling?
来
Here.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
-你们怎么...  -我们不会伤害你
- How did you-- - We're not going to hurt you.
你们是什么
What are you?
神子
Bene Elim.
用你们的语言说就是天使
Angels, in your language.
我们以人形与你见面
We come to you in human form.
天使
Angels?
我们只是想谈谈
We just want to talk.
别跟着我了
Stop following me.
伊萨哈特
AEsahaettr.
是真的
It's real.
飞行器应该是摔烂了
I think the craft is pretty much done for.
那我们要怎么回共和国去
And how will we get back to the Republic?
我们总会有办法的
We'll be able to figure something out.
有发现吗
See anything?
前路安全
Looks like the path is clear.
指挥官  我们去救人吧
Commander, let's go get our man.
跟我走
Follow my lead.
安全
Cleared.
安全了吗
We secure?
-安全 -安全
- Clear! - Clear!
安全了
All clear.
奥滚威
Ogunwe.
哪一位是奥滚威指挥官
Which one of you is Commander Ogunwe?
我是
I am.
你和你的小朋友是什么人
Who are you, and your little friends?
我是阿斯里尔·贝拉克瓦勋爵
I am Lord Asriel Belacqua.
我意图进军天堂王国
I intend to march upon the Kingdom of Heaven,
我很希望你可以加入我
and I should very much like you to join me.
我听说过你的事
I've heard stories about you.
你刚跟教廷宣了战
You have just made war with the Temple.
你自己去打吧
I'll let you fight that one.
听听他要说的话
Listen to what he has to say.
我和我的朋友并不来自你的世界
My friends and I, we are not from your world.
我们对你们的教廷没什么兴趣
We have little interest in your Temple.
我们是为你而来
We came here for you.
跟我一起抵抗权威者
Join with me in my fight against the Authority.
我知道我们有共同的立场
Look, I know that we stand for the same thing.
我知道你有多少手下
I know the number you command.
我想要你的军队  但我需要你做领袖
I want your army, but I need your leadership.
跟我来  加入最终的胜利
Come with me. Be a part of the final victory.
你可以跟我来
You can come with me.
欢迎来日内瓦  麦克菲尔主教
Welcome to Geneva, Cardinal MacPhail.
庭长神父  有请
Father President, please.
庭长神父
Father President.
跟我说说逮捕的情况
Tell me of this arrest.
我们在现场发现了这玩意
We recovered this material from the site.
它被当着众人背诵出来
It was recited before an audience,
很多人听得如痴如醉
many inebriated,
之后还进行了激烈讨论
and followed by feverish discussion,
和怪诞的思想交流
and a grotesque exchange of ideas.
诗
Poems.
杰罗姆神父
Father Jerome.
你觉得该怎么办
What do you think should be done?
应以异端邪说的罪名将作者监禁起来
The author must be imprisoned for heresy.
海斯特神父
Father Heyst.
整栋楼里还藏了数十本这样的书
There were dozens more like it hidden throughout the building.
所有出席者
All attendees imprisoned,
和所有持有作者著作的人都被监禁了
as well as anyone found in possession of the author's work.
你呢
Father?
-戈梅兹  -戈梅兹神父
- Gomez. - Father Gomez.
如果你是我  你会怎么做
If you were in my position, what would you do?
肉体赎罪  当众进行
Physical atonement... in public.
被诉持有此书的人
For those charged with possession,
我或许会选择鞭刑
I'd choose, perhaps, the whip.
至于作者
For the author,
采取能留下更持久伤痕的办法
something which leaves a little more... lasting damage.
恐惧是馈赠  能让人长进
Fear is a gift. It allows people to learn.
他们会把我们杀鸡儆猴
They'll make examples of us.
巴鲁克  我们没时间了
Baruch, we do not have time.
我们需要那把刀
We need that knife.
我叫你们别跟着我了
I told you to stop following me.
你们是怎么穿梭世界的
How can you cut through worlds?
我们是由尘埃构成的
We are made of Dust,
可以穿过空中无形的空间
and can pass through invisible spaces in the air,
那是通往其他世界的门
gateways into other worlds.
我们看得到  但你看不到
We can see them, but you cannot.
巴尔塞莫斯和我一直在寻找伊萨哈特
Balthamos and I have been searching for AEsahaettr...
还有你
for you.
因为一场大战即将来临
Because there is a great war coming.
所有有意识的生灵已经卷入了大战
All conscious beings are engaged in a battle already,
但不是每个人都知道
though not all of us know it.
敌人的力量每分每秒都在强大起来
The enemy's power is growing stronger every minute,
而你就持有能让我们获胜的武器
and you have the weapon that will enable us to win.
你得跟我们去找阿斯里尔勋爵
You must come with us to Lord Asriel.
他在召集军队
He's gathering an army
-意图...  -我知道他是谁
- with the purpose to-- - I know who he is.
有人跟我说过他  他的一切
Someone told me about him. About all of it.
战争
The war,
以及我要拿着它  跟阿斯里尔并肩作战
how I'm supposed to fight alongside Asriel, with this.
我不能跟你们走  抱歉
I can't go with you. I'm sorry.
我在找我的朋友  莱拉
I'm looking for my friend, Lyra...
阿斯里尔的女儿
Asriel's daughter.
虽然他不会在乎  但她失踪了
Not that he cares, but she's lost.
她需要我的帮助
She needs my help.
你不懂
You don't understand.
刀的重要性远超乎你的想象
That knife is more important than you can imagine.
不  是你不懂
No, you don't understand.
莱拉才是现在对我最重要的事
Lyra's the most important thing to me right now.
我要找到她
I'm going to find her.
-你要马上跟我们走  -不然呢
- You will come with us now-- - Or what?
你朋友的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your friend.
我看得出她对你来说很重要
I can see she means a lot to you.
你知道她遭遇了什么吗
Do you know what happened to her?
我们遭到了袭击  她被抓走了
We were attacked. She was taken.
-谁抓了她  -我不知道
- By who? - I don't know.
我撇下她先走了
I went ahead without her.
我还以为她不会有事
I thought she would be safe.
可我回来时  她就不在了
When I came back, she was gone.
不管阿斯里尔需要什么  让他等着吧
Whatever Asriel wants, he can wait.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你知道我们会一直跟着你
You do realize we're just going to keep following you
直到你回心转意
until you change your mind.
那你们就继续跟着我吧
Well, you can keep following me because...
每次我穿越后  你们都找到了我
You've managed to find me every time I've cut through.
怎么做到的
How?
刀  它吸引尘埃
The knife. It attracts Dust.
我们有人类不具备的感知
We have senses that humans do not.
帮我找到她
Help me find her.
如果你们能找到我  就能找到莱拉
If you can find me, you can find Lyra.
带我去找她
Take me to her.
然后  我就跟你们去找阿斯里尔
Then, I will come with you to Asriel.
我们没时间了
We do not have time.
巴鲁克  他们要不了多久就会找到我们
It will not take them long, Baruch. They will find us.
那我们就快点
So we will be quick.
巴尔塞莫斯  我们没别的办法
Balthamos, we don't have a choice.
这是莱拉的
This was Lyra's.
她说它跟刀是一个原理
She says it's powered the same way as the knife.
或许你可以用它找到她
Maybe you can use it to find her.
它是由尘埃驱动的
It's powered by Dust.
对
Yes.
我们需要点时间  但我们会找到她
We will need a little time, but we will find her,
不管她在哪个世界
whatever world she is in.
莱拉  我在这里
Lyra, I'm here!
等等  我来了
Wait, I'm coming.
罗杰  这是什么地方
Roger, what is this place?
我讨厌这里
I hate it!
罗杰
Roger!
我好怕
I'm scared!
罗杰
Roger.
来
Come on.
马琪
Machi!
父亲
Father!
天啊  我好想你
God, I missed you.
我的心肝  看看你
Oh, my sweet. Look at you.
你长高了15厘米
You've grown six inches,
你快跟我一般高了
you're almost as tall as me now.
爸爸还有工作  我就回来
Daddy has work to do. I'll be right back.
你女儿真可爱
You have a beautiful little girl.
你多久没见着她了
How long since you last saw her?
十个月零16天
Ten months and 16 days.
我本来没有可能能离开那监牢
I had no hope of leaving that cell,
直到你和你的猫
until you and your cat
跑来招募我
came to recruit me.
怎么了
What?
我在考虑你到底是疯子
Trying to decide if you're a madman...
还是天才
or a genius.
我倒希望两者可以共存
Well, I rather hoped the two could coexist.
阿斯里尔徐勋爵
So, Lord Asriel...
告诉我你的战争究竟是针对谁
tell me who your war is really against,
以及你想要我做什么
and what you want from me?
我要向权威者发起挑战
My fight is with the Authority himself--
你说过了  但这不可能
You said that before, but it's impossible.
人类不能反抗创世主
Humankind cannot stand against its Creator.
他逼我们在他脚边下跪
Well, he forces us to kneel at his feet,
但他并不是创世主
but he is not the Creator.
那都是谎言
It's all a lie.
他是个天使
He is an angel.
-天使  -仅此而已
- An angel? - Nothing more.
你又是怎么知道的
And how do you know all this...
即便这是真的
...even if it were true?
几千年前
Some millennia ago,
另一个天使发现了权威者的秘密
another angel discovered the Authority's secret.
那个天使  泽法妮娅  现在是我的理事会成员
Now, that angel, Xaphania, sits on my council.
奥滚威  我在召集各个世界的最强大的力量
Ogunwe, I am gathering the greatest from every world.
包括天堂的
From even the heavens above,
但我想请你来帮我掀起战争
but I want you to help me wage my war.
我该感到受宠若惊
I should be flattered.
我可是远道而来  这就对了
Well, I have come rather a long way, so yes, you should.
阿斯里尔勋爵
Lord Asriel...
我不能帮你
I cannot help you.
马琪是我的最小的女儿
Machi is my youngest daughter.
但我还有一个
But I have another.
教廷早就盯上了我们的孩子
The Temple have been targeting our children for a while now.
但近年来
But in recent years...
他们抓走了孩子们
they began taking them away...
进行训练
for training.
阿丽娅是教廷的财产
Aria... is the property of the Temple.
在她看来
To her...
我并不存在
I do not exist.
她只认权威者
There is only the Authority.
我所认识的女孩
And the girl I knew...
已经不在了
she's gone.
但她仍是我的孩子
But she's still my child.
我明白你提出的是什么
I understand what you offer.
但我还要打自己的仗
But I have my own battles here to fight.
我有义务尽我所能  拯救更多人的
And an obligation to save as many sons...
儿子和女儿
and daughters as I can.
我可以吗  拜托
May I? Please.
我见过这种情况  她的精灵被切割了
I've seen this before. Her daemon has been severed.
她才不是邪魔
She is not demonic.
我没那个意思  抱歉
I did not say she was. Forgive me.
拜托  请允许我解释  斯特尔玛丽娅
Please, if you'll allow me to explain. Stelmaria?
斯特尔玛丽娅和我是一体的
Stelmaria and I are one.
她是我的精灵  我的灵魂  也可以这么说
She is my daemon. My soul, if you use that word.
阿丽娅的精灵原本在她体内
Aria's daemon resided within.
我们和精灵之间的纽带
The link that binds us to our daemon
非常强大
is immensely powerful.
但一旦它被切断  便所剩无几
But when it is severed, well, very little remains.
他们在夺走我们的灵魂  奥滚威
They are taking our souls, Ogunwe,
同时也带走了我们的人性
and with them our humanity.
这样更好控制我们
To make us easier to control.
就把我们变成这样
To make us this.
无人机
Drones.
把马琪带回来  所有人进屋
Get Machi on the ground! Everyone, inside now!
别开火  他们想引我们出去
Hold your fire. They're trying to draw us out.
您找我  庭长神父
You sent for me, Father President?
请进  戈梅兹神父
Come in, Father Gomez.
我来日内瓦
I have come to Geneva
是因为一件要事
on a matter of great significance.
弗拉·帕维尔的真理仪让我得知了一则预言
Fra Pavel's alethiometer has informed me of a prophecy
如果是真的  我也相信它是真的
which, if true, a-- and I believe it is,
那么它或能让我们堕入黑暗
risks plunging us into a darkness,
那是世界前所未见的黑暗
the like of which the world has not experienced.
此时此刻  世上有一个女孩
There is a girl wandering the earth at this very moment,
她就是夏娃
and she is Eve.
我们所有人的母亲  一切罪孽的起源
The mother of us all, and the cause of all sin.
真理仪说  如果这个孩子被毒蛇诱惑了
The instrument says that if this child is tempted by the serpent,
她很可能会堕落
she will likely fall.
一旦她堕落  罪孽和尘埃就赢了
And if she does fall, then sin and Dust will triumph.
这绝不能发生
This cannot happen.
那我们就阻止她
So, we stop her.
她在哪
Where is she?
很遗憾  我们只能等
Unfortunately, we are at the mercy
真理仪和解读者怎么说了
of the instrument and its user.
弗拉·帕维尔的进展出奇的慢
Fra Pavel's work is unbearably slow.
等他找到这孩子
When he does locate the child...
我们就派兵去把她抓回来
we will send troops to retrieve her.
我想请你  戈梅兹神父  去带队
And I would like you, Father Gomez... to lead them.
我很荣幸
It would be an honor.
我可以去见见弗拉·帕维尔
I could perhaps drop in on Fra Pavel.
看能不能让他快点
See if I can speed him up a little.
请吧
Please.
这么多人在找你
All these men after you.
我说了  这不会变的
I tell you, it'll never change.
这世上有些力量
There are forces out there
你根本无法理解
that you can't begin to understand.
你还是别那么看我
I wish you wouldn't look at me like that.
难道你不希望我保护她吗
Would you rather I didn't keep her safe?
你在囚禁她
You're keeping her prisoner.
放了我们
Let us go.
恐怕不行
Afraid I can't.
你找到她了
You found her.
你是对的
You were right.
她是在精灵世界
She is in the world of the daemons.
在哪
Where?
她跟一个女人在一起  那女人强行控制着她
She's with a woman who is holding her against her will.
她们在一座岩洞屋里
In a house carved into the rocks.
那里位于北海上的一座偏远岛屿
It's on a remote island in the German ocean.
你需要乘船去
You will need passage on a ship.
但莱拉没受伤吗
But Lyra's not harmed?
对  只是在睡觉和做梦
No. Just asleep and dreaming.
可以跟我说说那女人吗
What can you tell me about the woman?
她的精灵是只金猴
Her daemon is a golden monkey.
-是她妈妈  -她妈妈
- Her mother. - Her mother?
莱拉如果跟她母亲在一起
Lyra's mother's the worst possible person
那就太糟了
she could be with.
巴尔塞莫斯会带你去找她
Balthamos will take you to her.
我得去找阿斯里尔
I must go to Asriel
告诉他你和伊萨哈特的事
and tell him about you and AEsahaettr.
你确定这样安全吗
Are you sure this is safe?
直接去找莱拉
Go straight to Lyra,
我们很快就将重聚
and we will be together again before long.
我可不记得我答应要陪着这男孩
I do not remember agreeing to accompany the boy.
跟紧威尔
Stay close to Will.
等孩子们重聚了
As soon as the children are reunited,
你们一起来阿斯里尔的共和国找我
you will both come to me in Asriel's Republic.
庭长神父麦克菲尔派我来的
Father President MacPhail sent me.
那女孩在哪
Where is the girl?
我快找到了  神父  我保证
I am close, Father. I assure you.
看来这任务对你来说是个重担
I see this task has weighed heavily on you.
如此压力  如此重大的责任
The pressure. Such great responsibility.
一定让你头脑很不清醒
It must muddle the mind terribly.
就是解读的最后部分
It is this... ...final part of the reading.
它的意义
Its... meaning...
我就是搞不懂
...eludes me.
我就是需要更多时间
I just need a little more time.
我们只能做我们能做的事
We can only do that of which we are capable.
庭长神父建议
Father President has advised
如果读不出坐标
that if the coordinates are not forthcoming,
那么或许现在需要  重新教育你
then perhaps, the time has come to re-educate you.
不
No.
不  我能找到她
No. I will find her.
我保证
I promise.
我毫不怀疑
I have no doubt that you will.
莱拉  求你  醒醒
Lyra. Wake up, please.
看啊
Look.
我们可以逃走
We can get away.
莱拉
Lyra!
她来了
She's coming.
你跑不掉的
You're not gonna make it.
我们总得试试
We have to try.
躲在这里  或许会有人看到我们
Hide here. Maybe someone will see us.
莱拉
Lyra?
Lyra!
她在哪
Where is she?
我看不到
I can't see.
莱拉
Lyra!
莱拉  你在哪
Lyra, where are you?
你总能让我惊奇
You never cease to amaze me.
不要
Please.
我明白你为什么要这样
I do understand why you're doing this.
这样跟我在一起感觉很奇怪吧
Must be strange being here, like this... with me.
但我带你来这里  不是为了关着你
But I haven't brought you here to keep you jailed.
我是为了保护你
I've done it to keep you safe.
莱拉  亲爱的
Lyra, darling...
有人要来抓你
there are people coming for you.
危险的人
Dangerous people.
你好勇敢
You're so brave.
勇气十足
So courageous.
我知道你不会相信我
I know you won't believe me,
但我这是为了你
but I... I am doing this for you.
来吧  亲爱的  来
Come on, darling, here you go.
我跟你在一起绝不会安全
I will never be safe with you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
指挥官  他们去矿山了
Commander, they're heading for the mines.
他们会跟我们拉开四英里距离
They will miss us by four miles.
很好  我们躲到天黑
Good. We'll stay covered until sundown.
努力反抗  指挥官
Putting up a good fight, Commander,
但你的战役太小了
but the battle you're engaged in is too small.
即便你赢得了对教廷的战斗
Even if you win this fight against the Temple,
权威者只会派来更多仆从替代他们
the Authority will send more servants in their place
逼你再次下跪
to put you back on your knees.
他们每个世界都有  我见识到了
They are in every world. I've seen it.
你总说什么其他世界
You keep talkin' of other worlds
好像指望我会相信
as if you expect me to believe them.
我没撒谎
I do not lie.
这只是众多世界中的一个
This is but one world among many.
每个世界里都在发生一样的事
In every single one of them, the same thing.
孩子被残害
Children, mutilated.
科学  学习  被视为罪行
Science, learning, criminalized,
整个文明在天空下瑟瑟发抖
and whole civilizations cowering under the sky.
我也曾像你一样
I was like you once.
在我的世界  我们的教廷叫教会当局
In my world, the Temple, they are called the Magisterium
我大半辈子都浪费在跟他们作战上了
and I have wasted most of my life fighting them
直到我发现  他们不过是权威者
until I discovered that they were but one arm
力量的一根手臂
of the Authority's might,
而那只野兽有无数手臂
and that beast has countless arms.
唯一值得你赌上孩子们的性命的战争
The only fight worth risking your children's lives for
在别的地方
lies elsewhere.
我在这地上的共和国
My Republic, down here in the good Earth,
反抗他天上的王国
against his Kingdom up there in the sky.
这是唯一获得胜利的办法
It is the only way to win.
我们砍掉野兽的头
We cut off the head of the beast,
剩下的便会分崩离析
and the rest will crumble.
不
No!
No.
你要我相信的事太难以置信
What you ask me to believe is too great.
是不容易接受
It's a lot to take in...
让我带你看吧
so, let me show you.
带我看
Show me?
这样你就可以自己决定了
And that way you can decide for yourself.
我带你去别的世界
Let me take you to another world.
拜托
Please...
别烦我
just let me be.
我会想到办法的
I'll think of something.
我以为他早该到了
I just thought he'd be here by now.
-你知道她是怎么读的吗  -不知道
- Do you know how she reads it? - No.
这些真理仪的解读者通常要学习很多年
Readers of those instruments have normally studied many years.
即便如此  他们也需要书籍
Even then, they can only understand
-才能进行解读  -她不是在瞎说
- with the help of books. - She wasn't making it up.
或许她很会...编
Perhaps she's a very... skilled inventor.
她会解读
She can read it.
它让她知道了她根本不可能知道的事
It told her things she could have never known,
比如我父亲在哪  这是她的一部分
like where my father was. It's a part of her,
就像刀是我的一部分
just like the knife's a part of me.
那就是我们在找的港口
That's the port we're looking for.
我们只需要找艘船了
Now, we just need a ship.
我是尤雷科·伯尔尼松国王
I am King Iorek Byrnison.
你们困住了我的一头熊
You've trapped one of my bears!
马上放了她
Release her now!
我可能认识那只熊
I think I know that bear.
-我可以跟他谈谈  -什么
- I can talk to him. - What?
那是莱拉的朋友
It's Lyra's friend.
她在哪
Where is she?
来啊
Come on!
停下
Stop!
Stop.
-让开  小子  -你得停下来
- Get out of my way, child. - You have to stop.
这里还有无辜者呢
There are innocent people here.
他们抓了一头我的熊
They have taken one of my bears!
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想一对一地跟你决斗
I want to fight you. In single combat.
我赢了  你就放过这些人
I win, you leave these people alone.
我输了
If I lose,
你可以随意处置他们和我
do whatever you want with them, and me.
你要跟我决斗
You wish to fight me?
跟你决斗是可耻的
It would be shameful to fight you.
你如一只离壳的牡蛎一般脆弱
You are as weak as an oyster out of its shell.
那我们让决斗公平点
Let's make it a fair fight, then.
你有盔甲
You have all the armor.
我没有
I have none.
给我一件
Give me a piece.
什么都行
Anything you want.
那我们就更势均力敌了吧
We'll be better matched then, won't we?
你知道你在做什么吗  小子
Do you know what you are doing, boy?
太空铁  是吧
Sky-iron, am I right?
坚不可摧  是吧
Impenetrable, I heard.
没想到啊
That's surprising.
看来我还是得不戴盔甲跟你决斗了
I guess I have to fight you without armor after all.
我打不过那个
I cannot fight that.
那把刀太奇怪了
That knife is too strange.
你赢了  小子
You win, boy.
马上放了那头熊
Free that bear, now.
你们听到了  快去
You heard the boy. Do it!
你叫什么  小子
What is your name, child?
威尔·佩里
Will Parry.
威尔·佩里  你在找莱拉
So, Will Parry, you're looking for Lyra?
她跟她母亲在一起  被她囚禁着
She's with her mother, being held against her will.
那我们得去救她
Then we must go to her.
庭长神父
Father President.
我去见了弗拉·帕维尔好几次
I visited Fra Pavel. Several times.
我帮他
I helped him to...
进一步
focus his mind...
集中了精神
a little.
他已判断出  那孩子
He has since divined that the child
正跟她妈妈在一起
is with her mother.
她母亲
The mother.
有了这个情报
With this information,
我相信我能找到那女孩
I am confident I can locate the girl myself.
但我需要使用没有得到
But I will need to use methods that aren't...
官方准许的手段
officially sanctioned.
你需要做什么就去做吧
You must do whatever you need to do.
一旦你知道了她们的方位
The second you have their position,
就去找她们  抓到那孩子和她妈妈
go to them, get the child, get the mother,
把她们直接带回来找我
and bring them directly to me.
玛丽莎·库尔特是毒妇  擅长摆弄人心
Marisa Coulter is evil, she is persuasive.
别信任她
Do not trust her.
神父  我成年之后  每一天都在预忏悔
Father, I've done pre-emptive penance every day of my adult life.
我会不惜一切
I will do whatever...
把她们抓回来
is required to get them here.
你对权威者的忠心不会白费
Your dedication to the Authority will not go unappreciated.
阿斯里尔
Asriel,
希望你不是在要我去送死
I do hope you're not walking me to my death.
死亡是谎言
And death is a lie.
你错了  死亡是真的
You're wrong. Death is real.
我见识过
I've seen it.
在无数战争中见过
More than my fair share of battle.
指挥官  权威者不知怎么
Commander, somehow the Authority
扭曲了尘埃的自然秩序
has managed to pervert the natural order of Dust.
我不知道他怎么做到的  但等我查清楚
I don't know how but when I find out,
相信我  死亡就会死
believe me, death is going to die.
我想我听的够多了
I believe I've heard enough.
你会看到的
You'll see.
斯特尔玛利娅  听我令
Stelmaria, on my mark...
咬下去
...I want you to bite down.
准备好了吗
You ready?
三  二  一
In three, two, one.
看
See?
欢迎来到天堂共和国  指挥官
Welcome to the Republic of Heaven, Commander.
你还是召集军队吧
I'd gather my people if I were you.
真正的战争要开始了  我们必须赢
The real war is coming, and we must win it.
缅怀海伦·麦克洛瑞
[斯特尔玛丽娅的配音演员]